

### Research Interest

My research interests lie in Embodied AI. My goal is to empower active agents with advanced skills in the complex and open world, through designing more robust algorithms and building more diverse environments, especially with the help of generative and foundation models.

# Education

Tongji University Shanghai, China

B.ENG. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, COLLEGE OF ELECTRONIC & INFORMATION ENGINEERING

Sep. 2019 - Jun. 2024

• GPA: 88.0/100 Overall Ranking: 4/113 (Top 3.5%)

**University of California San Diego** 

California, USA

VISITING STUDENT RESEARCHER AT SU LAB, JACOBS SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING

Mar. 2023 - Present

Advisor: Prof. Hao Su
 Peking University

Beijing, China

VISITING STUDENT RESEARCHER AT CENTER ON FRONTIERS OF COMPUTING STUDIES

Mar. 2022 - Present

· Advisor: Prof. He Wang

# **Publication**

\*: equivalent contribution, †: corresponding author(s)

# [C3] GAMMAP: Graspability-Aware Mobile MAnipulation Policy Learning based on Online Grasping Pose Fusion

Jiazhao Zhang\*, Gireesh Nandiraju\*, Jaylon Wang, Xiaomeng Fang, Chaoyi Xu, Weiguang Chen, **Liu Dai**, He Wang<sup>†</sup>

Submitted to IEEE Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2024

#### [C2] 3D-Aware Object Goal Navigation via Simultaneous Exploration and Identification [Paper Link]

Jiazhao Zhang\*, **Liu Dai\***, Fanpeng Meng, Qingnan Fan, Xuelin Chen, Kai Xu, He Wang<sup>†</sup>

Accepted to IEEE/CVF Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Conference (CVPR) 2023

#### [C1] Discovering Novel Categories in SAR Images in Open Set Conditions [Paper Link]

**Liu Dai**, Weiwei Guo<sup>†</sup>, Zenghui Zhang, Wenxian Yu

Accepted to IEEE/GRSS International Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium (IGARSS) 2022, Oral

# **Research Experience**

#### **University of California San Diego**

California, USA

RESEARCH INTERN AT SU LAB, ADVISED BY **PROF. HAO SU** 

Mar. 2023 - Present

#### Project: 3D Scene Generation for Embodied Tasks [On-Going]

Aiming to generate environments enriched with diverse scene layouts and objects, through extracting knowledge from generative models.

Peking University

Beijing, China

RESEARCH INTERN AT EPIC LAB, ADVISED BY PROF. HE WANG

Mar. 2022 - Present

### Project: Active 3D Scene Understanding & Object Goal Navigation [C2]

- Proposed the first 3D-aware framework for the challenging Object Goal Navigation task, empowered by two simultaneously running subpolicies: corner-guided exploration policy and category-aware identification policy. By this dedicated design, we overcame the challenge of low sample efficiency in RL and high computational cost when leveraging 3D data for training navigation skills.
- I contributed significantly to the method design, coding, and writing, and was primarily responsible for visualization in this project. It ignited my passion for Embodied-AI, further honing my skills in RL, coding, writing, and plotting.

#### Project: Mobile Manipulation in the Real World [C3]

• Introduced a fusion-driven, graspability-aware mobile manipulation method that ensures consistent temporal grasping pose observations. These observations can be encoded into a reward system, guiding the robot to emphasize detailed observations as it moves towards the best grasping positions. The approach's effectiveness was showcased through extensive real-world tests on a robot dog.

RESEARCH INTERN, ADVISED BY PROF. WEIWEI GUO

Sep. 2021 - Mar. 2022

#### Project: Remote Sensing Image Interpretation in the Open & Challenging World [C1]

- Introduced a multi-stage framework for discovering novel categories in remote sensing images. Initially, a representation extractor is trained using a self-supervised approach, optimizing the use of both labeled and unlabeled data. Subsequently, we estimate the number of new classes and cluster the unidentified data using open-set detection.
- This was my first research project, which ignited my research interest in the Open-World setting. I independently handled the majority of the coding, writing, and plotting.

# **Teaching**

## Course 55010501: Opensource Hardware and Programming

Tongji University

TEACHING ASSISTANT FOR PROF. XIAOHUA SUN IN COLLEGE OF DESIGN AND INNOVATION

2021 Fall

Delivered courses on Python & Arduino, guided undergraduate students to design and implement their Art projects through coding.

### **Honors & Awards**

#### PERSONAL HONORS

2023 **Pursuit of Excellence Scholarship** with 50000¥ ( $\approx$ 7000\$)

Tongji University

- Highest Honor for All Members of Tongji University (10/43106, among faculty, students & admin staff).

2022 **SenseTime Scholarship** with 20000¥ ( $\approx$ 3000\$)

SenseTime Co.,Ltd.

- Nationwide Selected 30 Undergraduates in the Field of Al.

2022 Tongji Academic Star

Tongji University

- Highest Honor for All Undergrads at Tongji University (15/18536).

#### **COMPETITION ACHIEVEMENTS**

2021 **National First Prize** of *Challenge Cup* Competition: Research Track

**Project:** We built a pest detection system based on deep learning to help the agricultural workers in the less-developed rural area in China, where there is a great lack of experts on pest detection and the farmhand could only diagnose based on some folk prescription before.

- Most Influential Research Competition among University Students in China.
- Best Record in College History.
- Team Leader.
- 2023 National Silver Award of Challenge Cup Competition: Entrepreneurship Track
  - Best Record in College History.
  - Team Leader.
- 2022 **Gold Award in Shanghai** of *Internet+* Competition
  - Team Leader.
- 2020 University Champion of FLTRP Cup National English Public Speaking Contest

## Skills

**Programming** C/C++, Python, LaTex, HTML & CSS, SQL, Arduino, Bash

**Frameworks** Pytorch, NumPy, OpenCV, Open3D, trimesh, Habitat Simulator

**Others** Public Speaking and Presentation

# **Languages**

Chinese Native
English Fluent
French Preliminary

# **Entrepreneurship**

I am the co-founder of **LunarAI**, an AI-Empowered Start-Up for Modern Agriculture.